This video is made possible by Shopify.
Around mid 2025, a certain type of video
starts appearing on social media.
Small-time influencers placing huge
weird bets on Poly Market. Things like
Donald Trump will publicly say
McDonald's this month and Jesus won't
return before GTA 6 comes out. Will
Trump say Will Trump go to China?
>> Trump say,
>> "Will Jesus Christ return before 2027?"
and the players almost never lose. Shaky
phone footage shows them in their living
rooms shrieking with joy. The videos
come with messages like infinite money
glitch, but something about them seems
off. So, a team of journalists from the
Wall Street Journal set out to
investigate. [music]
>> I was shocked that this mystery, I
guess, that we've been looking into at
that point uh had such a an easy answer,
such a dumb answer, something that was
really staring us in the face. He
uncovered an enormous scandal and what
might just be the most disgustingly
deceitful influencer campaign of recent
times.
>> I think that we were all a little bit
stunned that [music] this is the route
that the company chose to go.
>> A highly organized campaign laser
focused on tricking young people in the
United States.
>> It's a bombshell allegations. And I
really was like, well, why aren't more
people talking about it?
>> A campaign involving influencers big and
small, insider trading tips.
>> I know who's going to be featured on
Iceman. [music] By the way, I actually
can bet on all this
>> And a shady social media army acting on
covert instructions. [music]
>> I think consumers have a right to know
what the content is that they're seeing,
where it's coming from, if someone is
paying for it and who's [music] paying
for it. That's why we couldn't find any
of these trades in the database.
>> I just think it contributed to this idea
that we're living in a manufactured
reality.
>> Confirm.
Thanks to Katherine Long from the Wall
Street Journal, plus Maya Kaufman and
Jason Beefman from Politico for speaking
with us. This video is mainly based on
their brilliant investigations. Please
check them both out. Links are [music]
in the description.
Shane Copeland launches Poly Market in
New York in 2020. He's 22 [music] at the
time and calls his site a prediction
market. People place Poly Market trades
on the timing of missile strikes, on
whether Donald Trump will smoke weed
with Joe Rogan, and on the earth being
proven to be flat. It's marketed as fun,
young, and cool. It's bolstered by
celebrity endorsements and investment
from Donald Trump Jr. Poly Market,
alongside its main rival, Cali, quickly
makes prediction markets a phenomenon.
In 2025, Bloomberg reports that Copelan
is the youngest self-made billionaire
ever. Poly Market is valued at up to $15
billion, but since 2022, the site has
effectively been banned in the US.
Before that time, authorities say it was
operating a financial exchange without a
license or registration. Now, Poly
Market is trying to officially return to
America. In December 2025, it launched
an app that allows limited betting
focused on sports. Unlike the Poly
Market site, the app is approved by
American authorities. But Poly Market's
[music] plan to return is also
accompanied by an enormous social media
campaign, [music]
reaching millions of people, building a
brand that people trust. Shopify helps
you get your product and idea in front
of customers anywhere they are. Your own
[music] store, social media platforms,
or the shop app. Use the live view for
more insight on how exactly things are
going down, where and how your customers
shop. Something that's especially handy
with the, sorry to bring it up, upcoming
holiday season. We have our own online
clothing store that's been powered by
Shopify for years. It's kind of
fascinating to see how there's one guy
in Canada who shops every drop. The
purple shop [music] pay button ties it
all together with instant and easy
checkout. No need to re-enter details.
We know from experience that it really
helps your shop convert. Checkout tends
to be a big point of friction where you
can easily lose potential customers if
the experience isn't smooth and
familiar. If you've got an idea, stop
sitting on it. Start your Shopify store
right now at shopify.com/fern
or scan the QR code. Link is in the
description.
Starting around mid 2025, Poly Market
seems to take up more space online.
Political influencers call the
prediction site unbiased and real. Live
streamers discuss Poly Market trades.
>> What is Jeffrey Epstein confer to be
alive before 2027? Not going to lie,
yes. Let's get that poly going. it.
>> Hundreds of social media videos show
people placing huge weird bets, but
their stories seem a bit too good to be
true. It seemed like they were often
times winning tens of thousands of
dollars or sometimes they had, you know,
hundreds of thousands of dollars sitting
in their their polyarket accounts.
>> Poly market bets are public. So, the
journal team tries to trace some of the
big wins they see on social media.
>> But the more we tried to do that, the
more frustrated we got because we just
could not find these trades. We spent,
you know, I I think over a week trying
to look for [music] these trades and we
we couldn't find them. Felt like banging
our heads into a wall. It was miserable.
We had no idea what was happening.
>> They take a closer look at the videos
and eventually it clicks.
>> So, for instance, in one of the videos
that we looked at, you know, a creator
bet $1,000 on Trump to say McDonald's
and then he cut to himself watching a
video of Trump [music] speaking at an
event with golden arches behind him and
he says McDonald's and the creator jumps
up. He's so excited cuz he's just
appeared to have won $100,000. But in
actuality, that video was from several
months before uh the creator filmed the
video. It would not have won, right? The
bet would not have won had he actually
placed it on polymarket.com.
Something doesn't add up. But that
McDonald's bet video does seem to show
the guy using the Poly Market site.
Money placed, bet confirmed, confetti,
it's all there on screen. How is that
possible? Catherine and her team are
puzzled. Then one day, she gets a text
from a colleague
>> and he said, "Guys, I figured it out. I
was watching one of these videos and
instead of going to polyarket.com, this
creator went to another website called
pouyarket.com. [music]
We're like, poy market, what is poy
market? So immediately we type in
poyarket.com into our phones and we're
met with this password protected page.
[music] So we were obviously very
interested in what was behind that page.
The next day [music] I I went to work. I
was talking to my my editor John about
this and you know I I took his notepad
and I I wrote [music] I wrote out
poyarket.com and I was like John what we
realized is that if you capitalize the I
in poy market it looks exactly like
polyarket.com [music] this capital I
looks like an L. This is the way we
think that these creators have been
faking their trade. That's why we
couldn't find any of these trades in the
database because they're all fake.
[music]
>> The PO market dummy site looks almost
exactly like the real deal. Creators use
it to film themselves appearing to win
those huge bets. Bets that are never
actually placed and so don't show up in
the public records. But why fake these
bets? And what would have happened if
people had placed real money in these
cases?
The journalists check out the fake bet
wins in more than 100 videos. The
supposed wins in those videos add up to
almost $900,000.
>> And in reality, those creators and
anybody else who had placed identical
trades would have lost over $160,000. In
other words, this was not even a winning
strategy. These creators were not
showing a winning strategy.
>> The fake win videos aren't marked as
Poly Market ads or endorsements. [music]
Why post them? The team tracks down some
of the creators and asks. And [music]
well, they say Poly Market paid them to
film and post the fake win videos and
that they were explicitly ordered to not
show that they had been paid. The
content had to look authentic. The
creators were earning thousands of
dollars a month, between $2,000 or
$3,000 a month, which is is not
insubstantial for a college student
[music] performing part-time work, but
is a far cry from the earnings that they
were purporting to have made on
polymarket.com. Right?
>> Clips of the fake bets rack up millions
of views, and the creators have helped
going viral. Enter Clippers.
>> Those are people who typically live
offshore. They're paid a very small
amount of money to [music] create sock
puppet accounts and then repost videos
with the goal of trying to [music] make
content go viral.
>> Poly market hired a marketing firm to
manage an army of clippers reposting the
fake bet videos on Tik Tok, YouTube, and
Instagram. The Clippers were told not to
reveal that they too were paid for their
reposts.
>> They gave guidance on how to set up a
sock puppet account, [music] how to warm
it up so that it wouldn't get banned by
the platforms. They said explicitly like
don't list any affiliation with Poly
Market. You know, one of the managers of
these clipping campaigns in a message to
the Clippers from this group [music]
chat that we reviewed, he said, "Look,
if you have Poly or Poly Market in your
in your username, [music]
you're going to be banned. We're not
going to pay you." There was very
explicit guidance like do not associate
yourself with [music] Poly Market. Just
be natural, be organic. This isn't try
to make it look like it's not a paid ad
campaign. Try to make it look like it's
just a normal social media user
spreading [music] this content. The fake
bet poly market clips were viewed over
140 million times according to the
analytics provider Tubular. Under US
advertising laws, companies have to be
truthful about what they're promoting.
If you're paid to endorse a product, you
have to disclose it.
>> As we continued our reporting, uh as we
[music] reached out to the company and
and also the creators for comment, many
of the creators um deleted the videos
from their profiles or um [music] you
know hid their profiles or archived
videos.
Poly Market didn't respond to our
request for comment about its creator
campaign. Polyarket told the Wall Street
Journal in a statement that [music] it
was committed to maintaining accurate,
fair, and transparent markets. We are
part of a rapidly growing industry and
are constantly evaluating ways to
improve how we're engaging and earning
the trust of our audience. Poly Market
also told the Wall Street Journal that
it plans to conduct a comprehensive
audit of active promotional content.
But turns out there's even more to Poly
Market's shady social media campaign
than the fake win videos. Around the
time Catherine and the team get on the
case, Politico journalists uncover a
different covert marketing plan. They
find out about a series of payments made
by Poly Market's chief marketing
officer.
>> And through [music] investigating the
payments, we discovered that they were
going to people that were big names on
Twitter, on Instagram, [music] who
weren't disclosing that they were being
paid by this guy.
>> [music]
>> The Poly Market executive paid various
influencers big sums of money, often
thousands of dollars. The exec used a
personal PayPal account to send the
payments. [music] Many of the paid
influencers posted about Poly Market.
>> Pull out your phone real quick. There's
[music] a place called Poly Market,
polyarket.com. It's the only place where
you can bet on news, the election.
>> First and foremost, they're supposed to
be disclosing this. [music] There's
rules that maybe aren't getting tight
enforcement right now, but they exist
[music] for a reason. And the idea is
that there should be transparency, that
consumers have a right to know when
someone is promoting something because
they like it or because they believe in
it or because they're getting paid
[music] to.
>> A conservative influencer called Elijah
Schaefer did say he had a deal to
promote Poly Market. But when the
influencers the political journalists
looked at posted about Poly Market on X,
most of them didn't mention that Poly
Market paid them. The US Federal Trade
Commission says if you endorse a product
in social media, you should make your
connection with the brand obvious.
>> At the end of the day, the FTC [music]
has standards for people who are
influencers, who are content creators.
There are rules out there for this, and
that draws a relatively clear line in
[music] the sand.
>> Politico could confirm that the Poly
Market executive sent $350,000
to influencers and creators all through
the exec's personal PayPal account, but
the real figure may be much higher. The
executive sent a total of $2.5 million
to over 800 people over the course of 14
[music] months and the polyarket posts
keep coming
and oftentimes these posts are being
presented as if they're news
developments like breaking like Trump is
more likely to beat Biden or Zoran Mani
is more likely to win the mayoral
election and they're presented as if
like it's a news article or it's a news
development but really these people are
being paid often to promote bets on Poly
Market and We have no idea.
>> Nick Shirley mentions Poly Market
particularly often. The company's
executive transferred him thousands of
dollars. Shirley makes videos about
alleged fraud in the US. They go
massively viral and are featured on
mainstream news. And another thing to
take note of is Gavin Newsome right now
in Poly Market. He is the leading
nominee for the Democrats come 2028. All
this fraud taking place, all this waste
is taking place. Nobody really knows
what's going on. He was posting about
Poly Market. While he was posting about
his fraud investigations [music] in
Minnesota, he was actually wearing Poly
Market branded apparel. While he was
talking about that,
>> there's a 35% chance on Poly Market
right now that those people who helped
defraud the government will be deported
back to Somalia.
>> Nick Shirley didn't respond to our
request for comment. Poly Market didn't
respond to our questions about
influencers. Neither did the Poly Market
executive who reportedly paid
influencers through a PayPal account. A
Poly Market [music] spokesman told
Politico that partnerships with
influencers were part of its standard
business practices. [music] The
spokesperson told Politico, "We
routinely collaborate with a diverse
range of independent [music]
organizations, partners, and content
creators spanning the political spectrum
and constantly monitor, evaluate our
progress and make the necessary
adjustments in [music] order to achieve
our core mission of providing the most
accurate, transparent, and datadriven
market insights to a [music] global
audience. But there's more.
>> I want to say thank you for doing this.
Seriously."
Yeah. Um,
>> get some good ratings today.
>> We're going to get some good ratings.
>> Aiden Ross is a live streamer with
millions of subscribers on YouTube,
Kick, and Twitch. According to a journal
source, Ross had a multi-million dollar
deal with Poly Market.
>> You could bet if the United States
strikes Iran. That is crazy as
>> Remember that army of Clippers hired to
repost the fake Poly Market wins? Ross'
Poly Market content was promoted [music]
that way, too. Aiden Ross. Uh,
specifically, we found five clips that
had been [music] selected uh, for
promotion where Aiden Ross was talking
about how easy it would be for him to
insider trade or to manipulate a market
on Poly [music] Market, including clips
related to who Donald Trump would meet
that year or who uh, would be featured
on Drake's newest album.
>> I know who's going to be featured on
Iceman, by the way. I actually can
[music] bet on all this Who will
Trump meet in Okay, see, this is funny.
I can just make that happen.
Poly market paying to promote insider
trading tips might initially seem
stupid. On a standard betting site, if
you win a bet with long odds, it can
mean a huge loss for the betting
company. But on Poly Market, traders
winnings are paid for by stakes from
other traders, not by Poly Market.
Instead, Poly Market makes money from
fees on bets. It doesn't really matter
who wins or loses or if the odds are
crazy long. The more bets [music]
placed, the more money Poly Market
makes. Poly Market has always had an
interesting relationship with insider
trading. I mean, it it's illegal to
insider trade on commodities markets.
Poly Market also bans it or says that it
bans it on the platform. But Poly Market
has also promoted itself as the [music]
most accurate source of truth on the
internet and you know, Poly Market
leaders have said that its markets
encourage people to share information
that might not be widely available.
>> Aiden Ross didn't respond to our request
for comment. [music] Poly Market didn't
respond to our questions about its
relationship with Aiden Ross or
potential insider trading. Poly Market
told the Wall Street Journal that Poly
Market prohibits trading based on stolen
information, illegal tips, or
information obtained in a breach of a
duty of trust, confidentiality, or other
legal obligation. The company added that
Poly Market's market integrity framework
includes trade monitoring, onchain
transparency, reporting channels, and
escalation processes to detect, review,
and respond to suspicious activity.
Where appropriate, we engage with
regulators and law enforcement to
support the integrity of our markets.
The fake bet videos, the paid live
streamers, the influencers in branded
hoodies. Poly Market spends millions of
dollars on it all. What's the endgame?
Dumb money refers to inexperienced
casual gamblers. They're often young and
place bets with long odds. The kind
[music] of people depicted in the fake
bet win videos. But if you actually
place polymarket bets with long odds,
like those in the fake win videos,
you're likely to lose money. In fact, a
recent study found that around 85% of
Poly Market traders lose money overall.
And only 2% have won more than $1,000 in
total. But luring new dumb money means
more trading fees for Poly Market. And
because polyarket winners are paid with
money from its losers, more dumb money
means more funding for the winners
betting against them.
>> So prediction markets are stacked
against the average person. There's a
huge group of, and this is the technical
term, unskilled losers consistently
losing a significant [music] amount of
money.
>> Kristoff made a great tunnel vision
episode on Poly Market and why you're
likely to lose on it. Go check it out.
The link is in the description. So the
people who consistently win on Poly
Market need the people who consistently
lose. Some Poly Market users even track
badly performing users accounts [music]
so they can make opposite trades.
>> Both Poly Market and Kelshi are focused
very heavily on growth. Um [music]
they're focused on attracting new users.
And part of the rationale for that is
that in order for the current user base
to find trading on [music] the platform
to be fun and profitable, there needs to
be a steady stream of new users that are
providing liquidity to the growing
number of markets that [music] both
platforms are offering. But Poly Market
isn't targeting just any dumb money. The
Clippers hired to repost fake win videos
are given a strict rule. They'll only be
paid if a large amount of their audience
is based in the US.
>> They were swapping tips, you know, like
how how do I make it seem like I live in
the United States and some of the
clippers were saying use a [music] US
SIM card or here find a US phone number.
>> Why is Poly Market targeting people in
the US when its site is still officially
banned there?
In mid [music] 2025, with these social
media campaigns up and running, Poly
Market paid over $und00 million to
acquire a licensed American exchange and
clearing [music] house. Poly Market
founder Shane Copelan says it paves the
way for us to welcome US traders again.
Poly Market's American app launched soon
after. And of course, the journalists
also found creators posting fake bet
videos using a fake Poly Market app.
They'd pivoted from just using the
[music] fake website.
The impact of the Wall Street Journal
and political reporting is immense. A
consumer protection group sued Poly
Market shortly after, partially citing
the journalism. The lawsuit accuses Poly
Market of running flagrantly deceptive
social media marketing and [music]
claims that teenagers saw the content. A
Commodity Futures Trading Commission
investigation into Poly Market is also
ongoing. Questions about insider trading
made it to the president.
>> Was he betting that they would get him
or they wouldn't get him? It sounds like
he was betting on his removal.
>> But still, Poly Market's rise seems to
continue. The company embedded itself
deeply into the culture, politics, and
media. [music] It partnered with Yahoo
Finance and Dow Jones, which owns the
Wall Street Journal. This is disclosed
in the Wall Street Journal's reporting.
Donald Trump Jr. invested in Poly Market
and has become an official adviser.
>> I think that [music] Donald Trump Jr.'s
role in Poly Market is so far somewhat
unclear to me.
>> I'd love to know more about that. Yeah.
The FBI raided Shane Copelan's home in
2024 toward the end of President [music]
Biden's term. At the time, authorities
were investigating Poly Market for
allegedly allowing American users on its
banned site. But after Donald Trump
returned as president, [music] things
eased up. An older CFTC investigation
into Poly Market was dropped within half
a year of Trump returning to office. And
Trump senior [music] has a word for
people who want prediction markets to be
federally regulated.
the Trump administration [music] has
been more lazy fair about it and if
anything encouraging I would say that
he's allow he's allowing these markets
to exist
once upon a time a huge deceitful social
media scandal like this might have led
to a company reckoning now we're not so
sure this story should [music] at least
serve as a reminder that we should
always always think hard about why an
influencer posts about something in this
particular ular case, it's hard to
imagine the creators didn't realize who
[music] they were targeting. Young
people who trust them set up to lose and
feed their savings into a machine that
has [music] to grow at all costs. So
much of what we consume is online and on
social media, but we actually have no
idea of the motivations behind the
posting or [music] what's going on
behind the scenes. And it was shocking,
but I just think it like again
contributed to this idea that like we're
living in sort of [music] like a
manufactured reality.